Will TRT solve all my libido issues?
It's a good one. Yeah, potentially.
Potentially. If you don't have
testosterone, that will affect your
libido most likely. So, like um but you
need more than that to have libido. So,
if you you know, you got to have a
partner you're attracted to. You've got
to have other lifestyle things that are
um addressed as well. You may or may not
have other co-orbidities going on that
are affecting it. So if you're feeling
generally unwell, you're probably not
going to have much of a libido. That's
not commonly what I see. Most commonly
what I see is just men often with no
other health conditions with low libido
secondary to testosterone. And in those
patients, it does work. But the one
thing to think of is a lot of people
when they start testosterone replacement
therapy expected to be like an on-off
switch. So I take it and I'm better. And
sometimes it takes a long time for that
to happen. So you can end up with a lot
of symptoms of low testosterone. So you
can have uh you're losing muscle mass no
matter what you do. You're gaining body
fat. You can have like um psychological
symptoms. You're very stressed, things
like this. Uh brain fog and those
improve at different rates. So sometimes
what I've seen is I'm I've got all this
muscle mass back and I feel sharp, but
the libido is not there. What's going
on? Or the other way around, the libido
comes back, but nothing else. And that's
the one thing you're not really in
control of at the start. You kind of
just got to be patient with it and and
just wait to see what happens. And I
often tell patients, don't really have
any expectations for six months. Often
you do you get something some benefit a
lot faster than that. But I think six
months is a good benchmark and that's
take that lets us take into account your
bloods and get everything right because
we don't always get it right at first.
Sometimes your levels are too high or
too low both of which can give you
symptoms you don't really want. Um, and
the other thing with the beo is it just
go into it relaxed and just don't don't
have any expectations of the treatment.
Just see what happens. I think if you're
always anxious about something, that
will also tank your libido significantly
as well.
Is that one of the most common low
symptoms you hear men complain about?
Low libido. It's up there. But funnily
enough, the thing that bothers men more
than low libido tends to be this
tiredness. So, they're saying like, "I'd
like to have libido. I find my partner
attractive and all of this, but I'm so
tired. I just want to feel not tired
first, then I'll worry about the rest."
Um, so which logically makes sense
really, but libido is a very very common
one. Yeah. Um, and different people are
in a different um stage of relationship
or in different kinds of relationship
where a low libido can be life ruining
really. it could end marriage and things
like this in some cases. Other cases
partner's not really that bothered and
they just want the partner better. So it
that's where the like tailor made
approach and taking people's own
lifestyle into account comes in
[Music]